Erica Thompson

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

•

702-302-3184



linkedin.com/in/ericathompsonsmiles



Erica-Thompson-Portfolio-Page/



ericathompsonsmiles@gmail.com



github.com/Younique98

ABOUT ME

Computers have been a part of my life since I was around 10 years old. Tinkering with computers inspired my career in technology when I started using that knowledge to fix other family member's computers to make spending money in middle school. I became certified at John A Logan College and my entry point into the tech world was repairing and troubleshooting the computers for local small businesses. I've been in the space for 6+ years, worked at Hype Media for 3 of them later as a DevOps Engineer for a non-profit. Finally, I have a love for helping companies and enjoy doing so by helping build scalable applications on a team utilizing modern technologies and solutions.

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

Languages: React, JavaScript, CSS, Python, SQL Systems: Windows PC, Mac OS X

Server, and iOS

Databases: Relational Databases, JSON **Software**: Salesforce/Amazon S3/Jira

CERTIFICATIONS

- Fonteva Platform Power User
- Fonteva Database Specialist
- Fonteva Events Power User
- AWS Public Sector Summit Course Completion
- G Suite Administration
- Salesforce Lightning Trailhead Academy
- CompTIA Project+

TECHNICAL EDUCATION

Software Engineer Apprentice

2019 - 2020

Nashville Software School- Nashville, TN

Intensive full-time 6-month software development Bootcamp anchoring learning with both individual and team-based projects

- Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, SQL, React, JSON
- Work on building the front-end code associated with websites, web apps, and hybrid mobile applications
- Connected front-end code to server code through open web APIs or custom web services
- Monitored all systems and traffic to ensure maximum availability, performance, and response rates
- Used server-side development concepts, such as test-driven development, object-oriented programming, pair programming, source code control in a team environment
- Learned common code patterns. SQL database access.
- Utilized Git and Github for version control
- Studies focused on Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, and Server-side fundamentals with Python and Django

PROJECTS

The Magical Witch | View code | Personal Project | Live Site |

- Developed an application using ERD and Project Wireframe that allowed users to easily create and save Horoscope readings.
- Integrated API library for users to effortlessly capture their notes and Tarot readings.
- Incorporated persistent data storage to archive user's thoughts.

Utilized: React, CSS, JavaScript, HTML, API, JSON, Cloudinary, AWS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project Desk Manager & DevOps Engineer 2019 - 2020 Online Learning Consortium - Boston, MA

- Ensure the stable operation of computer hardware, software systems, and network infrastructure, including servers, and VOIP telephony. Oversaw integration of Salesforce oversaw a team of 3 while reporting directly to the director. Install, deploy, support, AWS utilization, and maintain all virtual desktop infrastructure (VDI) and virtual application environments
- Monitor all systems and traffic to ensure maximum availability, performance, and response rates
- Diagnose and provide root cause analysis for deliverability issues, application, hardware, network, and O/S issues.
- Coordinated the design, implementation, operation, and maintenance of email systems, cases, networks, and cloud space for corporate systems such as **EC2**, **S3**, **AppSync**, etc
- Perform in-depth analysis and detailed reporting on **VDI** capacity planning, **SLA** performance, operating stem, and major application software patch assessment and security vulnerability analysis
- Review and update service policies and procedures to safeguard critical systems, information, and data
- Create and maintain high-quality documentation of all relevant specifications, systems, and procedures
- Assist in the development of processes to maintain business continuity and recovery standards
- Assist in building fully operating Conference App, tested with Test Flight, and deployment to App Store
- QA during the testing and development of sites and Conference app with a collaborative approach while maintaining that quality is ensured throughout the testing and delivery cycle.

Web Developer & Digital Marketer 2013 - 2019 Hype Media - Brentwood, TN

Completed performance trend analysis and managed server/network capacity. Designed, Developed, and Presented full websites using JavaScript, Drupal, WordPress & CSS

- Managed network architecture, databases, email and file servers, security, analytics tracking, social media accounts, digital marketing, and hosting and increased upsell by 35%, \$24,000/year.
- Project Management of key marketing and cross-functional projects while utilizing the marketing dashboards/scorecards for the marketing organization.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Software Developer 2021 Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN

JavaScript, React.JS, Python, Django, SQL

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science 2020 - 2022 Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT

- Courses included IT Project Management, Data Management, IT applications, Cloud Foundations, and Emerging Technologies
- Studies focused on IT Foundations, logic, architecture and systems, data structures, AI, and Computer Theory

Associates of Science 2018 - 2019 Hopkinsville Community College, Hopkinsville KY

- Introduction to information systems, computer applications, program development, system maintenance, networking, security, Internet technologies, database design, and collaborative system development
- Programming- Software Development track to prepare students to design, develop, and maintain computer programs written in current and emerging programming languages.